<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-03T23:23:58+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Ruby on Wheels</title><subtitle>A developer on the road.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Preventing my van going up in flames</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/02/preventing-my-van-going-up-in-flames.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preventing my van going up in flames" /><published>2017-05-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/02/preventing-my-van-going-up-in-flames</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/02/preventing-my-van-going-up-in-flames.html">&lt;p&gt;It has been raining a lot for the last weeks in Berlin. I urged installing the solar panels so I drove around to find a bridge that offers a dry place to work on the roof. While driving in the rain I realized that the wipers moved very slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t find any issues with the wipers or the motor. However I observed that the blinkers also flashed a bit weakly. While diving deeper into the issue I realized that several electric devices operated weakly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the headlights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the blinkers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the wipers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the fan for the heating&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;several lamps on the instrument panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to start looking for the root cause of all these problems? :thinking: With the help of the wire diagram I tracked the issue down to the fuse box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7618.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Wire diagram for a Mercedes-Benz 207D/209D&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All fuses seemed intact however some connectors looked really bad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7117.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Fuse box in bad condition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some cables even looked scorched:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7118.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Fuse box in bad condition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some of these connectors I measured a resistance above 200 Ω. :scream: The connectors were held together by bolts that got loose over time. These loose connections caused very bad conductivity, resulting in a lot of heat which further led to corrosion. A vicious circle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignoring this issue might have resulted in my van going up in flames. :fire:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All shops I checked were out of stock (part number &lt;em&gt;A0015450001&lt;/em&gt;) so I sanded all the connectors,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7599.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sanding the connectors&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;replaced the loose bolts with proper screws and linked the connectors with a thick copper sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7612.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Screws replacing the loose bolts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before installing the fuse box back into the van I measured the resistance of every single fuse connection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7614.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Repaired fuse box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All connections below 1 Ω. Yay, another fixed issue! :heavy_check_mark:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing the solar panels will hopefully the next project! :pray:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It has been raining a lot for the last weeks in Berlin. I urged installing the solar panels so I drove around to find a bridge that offers a dry place to work on the roof. While driving in the rain I realized that the wipers moved very slowly.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Breaking into my own van</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/26/breaking-into-my-own-van.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Breaking into my own van" /><published>2017-03-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/26/breaking-into-my-own-van</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/26/breaking-into-my-own-van.html">&lt;p&gt;All of sudden the door of the bathroom wouldn’t open any more. It seemed like the door lock broke. Too bad that all screws of the bathroom construction are inside. I had to disassemble the roof window to access the bathroom from the top. Obviously it’s not too hard to break into a camper van. :thinking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I was inside the bathroom I replaced the broken door lock with a new one that I found on eBay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7047.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Broken bathroom lock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the brackets holding the table in the back also looked very fragile. Once I’ve touched it, it just fell apart:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7084.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Broken bracket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t find a compatible replacement, so I rebuilt the bracket out of aluminum which seemed way more solid than the original plastic version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7083.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Self-made bracket replacement&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While investigating the whole vehicle in more detail I also realized some moldered wood at the back behind the bumper. The sealing was completely gone and after removing the bumper you could see how the wood had soaked up the water over time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7085.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Moldered wood behind the bumper&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a bit shocked but luckily only the bottom part was moldered. I removed the bad parts…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7089.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Removed moldered wood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… got rid of all the old glue, fixed the holes on the bottom panel and finally sealed everything with Dekalin, a sealant used by several camper manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7099.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sealed bumper&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started to rain the very next day and the wood behind the bumper stayed all dry. Another fixed issue and new lessons learned about what to check when buying a used camper van! :heavy_check_mark:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can’t wait to start the work I’ve originally planned to do: installing the solar system and the router for the mobile internet. Once these are ready I can finally hit the road and work remotely from everywhere. :minibus: :sunny: :computer:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">All of sudden the door of the bathroom wouldn’t open any more. It seemed like the door lock broke. Too bad that all screws of the bathroom construction are inside. I had to disassemble the roof window to access the bathroom from the top. Obviously it’s not too hard to break into a camper van. :thinking:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The first technical issue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/15/the-first-technical-issue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The first technical issue" /><published>2017-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/15/the-first-technical-issue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/15/the-first-technical-issue.html">&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;http://sayulitacowork.com/&quot;&gt;co-working&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sayulita,+Nayarit,+Mexico/@20.8697947,-105.4475249,15z&quot;&gt;paradise&lt;/a&gt; for a few weeks and visiting my co-workers at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/GitHub/@37.7822713,-122.3934366,17z&quot;&gt;HQ&lt;/a&gt;, I found an oil puddle below the transmission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7027.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Oil puddle below the van&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking closer I realized that the transmission was completely covered in oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7030.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Transmission leaking oil&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7059.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Transmission leaking even more oil&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might be connected with the wrong timing I’ve experienced during my &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/02/04/the-first-ride.html&quot;&gt;first ride&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked the oil level of the transmission. &lt;strong&gt;Something I should have done before buying the van!&lt;/strong&gt; Even though the transmission had already leaked a lot of oil the level was still above the &lt;em&gt;max&lt;/em&gt; marker. Obviously the person who changed the oil filled too much oil into the transmission. Too much or too little oil is something critical and can damage the transmission!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I carefully removed some oil with a hand pump until the level seemed about right: pump out, test drive, measure, repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_7081.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Pumping out oil from the transmission&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing of the transmission improved. When the engine is warm, gears are switched almost exactly like described in the official specs. However when the engine is still cold the transmission switches a bit too late into the next gear. As this is my first Mercedes-Benz I can’t tell if this is normal behavior or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general I consider the issue as fixed: the timing improved and the transmission doesn’t leak any oil anymore! :heavy_check_mark:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll regularly check the oil level of the transmission and keep an eye on it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After co-working in paradise for a few weeks and visiting my co-workers at HQ, I found an oil puddle below the transmission.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The first ride</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/04/the-first-ride.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The first ride" /><published>2017-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/04/the-first-ride</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/04/the-first-ride.html">&lt;p&gt;On my way back from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-merge.com/&quot;&gt;Git Merge&lt;/a&gt; conference in Brussels, I picked up the camper van near Düsseldorf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first ride started with 188,987 km on the odometer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6767.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Odometer before the first trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google told me that I should make the 566 km to Berlin within five hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6766.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Route from Düsseldorf to Berlin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However with 88 horsepowers, 2.6 tons and a straight windshield, you can’t take advantage of the German highways without speed limits. I mostly cruised behind trucks with an average speed of 85 to 90 km/h. :wink:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6773.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Driving on the highway&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving the van felt awesome: a lot of space, a comfortable seat high up, the sound of the diesel engine, the huge steering wheel and the simple instruments. Everything you need for a relaxed ride. This is the right vehicle for me! :+1: :heart:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently Google was wrong. With 85 km/h you can’t make 566 km in five hours. After about 300 km it was already dark and I decided to spend my first night in the van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around February it’s still cold in Germany: -2°C (~ 28°F). Time to test the heating, my sleeping bag and the mobile SIM-card to watch movie on Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6777.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sleeping bag in the alcove&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a great feeling, I can sleep wherever I stop. My bed is always with me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another 250 km the next day and the van was finally in Berlin! :tada:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6790.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;The camper van parked in Berlin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In average I burned about 13 liters of diesel on 100 km (~ 18 mpg). Compared to what I’ve read online, this seems like an acceptable consumption. I also noticed that the timing of the automatic transmission is not perfect. The first hidden issue to investigate! :wrench:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to start working on the van once I’m back from my trip to &lt;a href=&quot;http://sayulitacowork.com/&quot;&gt;Mexico&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On my way back from the Git Merge conference in Brussels, I picked up the camper van near Düsseldorf.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My future mobile office</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/11/my-future-mobile-office.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My future mobile office" /><published>2017-01-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/11/my-future-mobile-office</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/11/my-future-mobile-office.html">&lt;p&gt;Today I’ve checkout my future mobile office near &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/D%C3%BCsseldorf,+Germany/@51.2385861,6.6742667,11z&quot;&gt;Düsseldorf, Germany&lt;/a&gt;: A Mercedes-Benz 209D from 1984.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6432.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Mercedes-Benz 209D camper van&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s equipped with a small kitchen (fridge, stove and sink),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6442.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;kitchen in the camper van&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a table with two benches on the left and right that can be transformed into a bed,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6443.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;table in the back of the camper van&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and a bathroom with a foldable sink and a chemical toilet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_6444.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bathroom in the camper van&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transporter was originally a 207D with the OM 616 engine. However the four cylinder engine got replaced by a OM 617 engine. So now the van is operated with five cylinders and is technically equivalent to a 209D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the camper van seemed to be in good condition for its age. Little rust, engine started and ran smoothly and there was no musty smell inside. Of course it’s an old camper van that’ll need some TLC and I’m quite sure once I start working on it I’ll encounter all the hidden issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I immediately fell in love with the van and made the deal! :tada:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current owner imported the van from Netherlands but never registered the vehicle in Germany. He’ll organize all required papers and in a few weeks I’ll register the van and drive it to Berlin!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today I’ve checkout my future mobile office near Düsseldorf, Germany: A Mercedes-Benz 209D from 1984.</summary></entry></feed>